思いを馳せるのって
干渉もできない
"Thinking back in time." It's frustrating.
タイムマシンみたいで
なんか歯痒いね
It's like a time machine that
can't interfere with anything.
3Dのレンズして感動だけ貰って
I just want to put on my 3D glasses and be impressed.
ポップコーンつまんで
覗いていたいね
I just want to peek through them
while eating popcorn.
何か落とした気がして戻った
教室の灯り消えて暗いはずなのに
I came back because I thought I dropped something.
The lights were off in the classroom
誰かいるような気がして
ドア開けたら十数年前の俺じゃん！
But I felt like there was someone in there,
I open the door and it's me from a decade ago!
大人になってなんでもなれると
思い込んでたらやっぱ苦労したね
I thought I could be anything I wanted to be when I grew up,
but I knew I'd have a hard time.
までもおかげで知り合えた人たちもいるし
いい歌詞かけるし
But I've gotten to know some people,
and I can put on some good lyrics.
トントンってことで！
I'll take it easy!
あぁいつか
この景色も切り取られてアルバムになるから…
Someday this view will be cut out
and made into an album.
そしたら君に
話してあげるよ多分
I'll tell you about that then.
Maybe.
そろそろ帰んなきゃね
習い事の時間だったね
I should probably get going.
It's time for my lesson.
木の葉の浮かぶプールサイド
校舎の裏の車道
By the pool with the leaves floating in the trees,
and the driveway behind the school building.
ハッキリしなきゃだなんて…
いややっぱりやめとこうって
Do I need to clarify?
I knew I shouldn't have.
持ち帰る鞄と手紙と…どんなに素敵だろう！
I'll take the bag and the letter home.
How wonderful!
どんどん加速してる
鼓動音を追い越してる
It's accelerating.
It's overtaking the sound of your heartbeat.
もう見えなくなるくらいに
弧を描いてる光
I can't see it anymore.
The light that's arcing.
どんどん加速してる
鼓動音を追い越してる
It's accelerating faster and faster.
It's overtaking the sound of my heartbeat.
もう見えなくなるくらいに
ノスタルジックマジック！
So fast that you can't see it anymore,
It's Nostalgic magic!
息継ぎもせず一気に
4、5メーターほど泳いだら
All at once without even a breath.
I swam about four or five meters.
花火のようなこの数年間も
少しくらい報われるかな
I'd be a little rewarded for
all these years of fireworks.
ひたすら企みもなく、がむしゃらに
自分の形を確かめるように
I've spent them all without a plan,
just going through the motions, as if to check my own shape.
もうお開き、青春おしまい！
I'm done, my youth is over!
第2章も…乞うご期待！
Chapter 2...stay tuned!
ねぇ、いつか…
あの景色と違うアルバムのページになるから
Hey, someday...
you'll have a different view and a different page in your album.
そしたら、きっと許してあげるよ多分
And then maybe I'll forgive you.
そろそろ帰んなきゃね
アルバイトの時間だったね
I should probably get going.
It's time for my part-time job.
塗り重ねた階段の手すりと踊っていたいかも
I might want to dance with
the painted railing on the stairs.
さよなら…やっと言えたね
放課後、自転車置き場で
Goodbye... finally.
After school, at the bike yard.
振り返るスローモーション、カットバック
Looking back, slow motion, cut back
どんなに素敵だろう！
How wonderful!